A Guide to the James J. Kilpatrick Papers 1967-1972
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
The James J. Kilpatrick Papers, 1967-1972
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6626-d
2000 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The Library acquired these papers from James J. Kilpatrick on 30 Apr 1973, and Jan 1975.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains background material and correspondence relating to Kilpatrick's syndicated column, various articles, and speeches. Tapes of interviews, many from Meet the Press, are included. Among the participants are Reuben Askew, James Buckley, Angela Davis, Robert P. Griffen, Michael Mansfield, John Mitchell, Edmund Muskie, George Meany, Ralph Nader, James M. Roche, William Scranton, and George Wallace.
Contents List
- Correspondence: A-J Dec 1971-Dec 1972, 8 folders (Box 1)
- Correspondence: K-S Dec 1971-Dec 1972, 6 folders (Box 2)
- Correspondence: T-Z Dec 1971-Dec 1972 (Box 3)
- Background Material: Presbyterian Activist Column Jun 1971 (Box 3)
- Correspondence: Presbyterian Activist Column Jun 1971-Jan 1972 (Box 3)
- Correspondence: Episcopal Book of Common Prayer Column Jan-Feb 1972, 2 folders (Box 3)
- Eugene McCarthy: Article, News Clips, Information 1968 (Box 3)
- George Wallace: Article, News Clips, Information 1968 (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous Articles and Reviews n.d. (Box 4)
- Calendars: Contain lists of appointments 1969-1971 (Box 4)
- Calendar: Schedule, list of appointments (1 large calendar for each month) Jan-Dec 1972 (Box 4)
- Thesis (M.A.) on James Kilpatrick and the Richmond News-Leader by Samuel Banks, Howard University Jun 1970 (Box 4)
- Speeches, Correspondence, Notes, Miscellaneous Jan-Nov 1967, Jan-May 1972 (Box 5)
- Tapes
  - T-335: David Suskind Show (with Kilpatrick, Moyers, Galbraith, Baker, and Alexander) 23 Nov 1969
  - T-336: International Platform Association at Sheraton Hall (Kilpatrick and U.S. Attorney General John Mitchell) 28 Jul 1970, reel 1
  - T-337: International Platform Association 28 Jul 1970, reel 2
  - T-338: "TV News on Campus Commission" Report; "Meet the Press" Interview: William Scranton, James Ahearn, & Joseph Rhodes, Jr. of President's Commission on Campus Unrest 26-27 Sep 1970
  - T-339: Angela Davis Interview - Jail; Re: congressional Seniority System 17 Dec 1970; 15 Jan 1971
  - T-340: Senator Mansfield (on NET TV); Senators Muskie and Griffin (on NBC-CBS) 26 Jan 1971
  - T-341: "Meet the Press" Interview: Ralph Nader 30 May 1971
  - T-342: U.S. Supreme Court decision re: the "Pentagon Papers" (NBC TV special report, and radio editorials) 30 Jun 1971
  - T-343: "Meet the Press" Interview: James Roche of General Motors 25 Jul 1971
  - T-344: "Meet the Press" Interview: Governor George Wallace 22 Aug 1971
  - T-345: "Meet the Press" Interview: (George) Alexander Heard (Chancellor of Vanderbilt University) 30 Aug 1970
  - T-346: "Meet the Press" Interview: Senator James Buckley 22 Nov 1970
  - T-347: "Meet the Press" Interview: George Meany (AFL/CIO) 11 Jul 1971
  - T-348: "60 Minutes" ABC TV Documentary re: Nixon Supreme Court Nominees, with CBS, NBC, and ABC Editorials 21 Oct 1971
  - T-349: "Meet the Press" Interview: Governor Askew; "60 Minutes" (ABC TV documentary) 5 Mar 1972
- "Spectrum" Commentaries for Columbia Broadcasting System, Radio and Television 1972
  - Air Lines 11 Sep, 2 Nov 1972
  - American Newspapers Guild 3 Aug 1972
  - American Party 4 Oct 1972
  - August, Month of 27 Jul 1972
  - Bicentennial 28 Jun, 15 Aug 1972
  - Birds 26 Oct 1972
  - Budget, U.S. 6 Jul 1972
  - Bureaucracy 13 Jul 1972
  - Capital Punishment 6 Jul, 15 Nov 1972
  - CIA 21 Jun 1972
  - Confidence 15 Nov 1972
  - Congress 29 Nov 1972
  - Democratic Party 13 Jul 1972
  - Education 15 Aug, 26 Oct, 14 Dec 1972
  - Energy 17 Oct 1972
  - Environment 3 Aug, 21 Nov 1972
  - Federal Trade Commission 14 Jun 1972
  - Gun Control 28 Jun 1972
  - Independence Day 28 Jun 1972
  - Indians 15 Nov 1972
  - Labor Day 30 Aug 1972
  - Life Magazine 15 Dec 1972
  - Little Orphan Annie 31 May 1972
  - Marijuana 29 Nov 1972
  - McGovern, George 20 Jul, 28 Sep (TV), 28 Sep (CBS Radio), 17 Oct, 20 Oct 1972
  - Minimum Wages 31 May
  - Nader, Ralph 4 Oct 1972
  - National Defense 30 Aug 1972
  - Nixon, Impeachment 7 Jun 1972
  - No Fault Insurance 7 Jun 1972
  - Nursing Homes 6 Sep 1972
  - Pioneers 20 Oct 1972
  - Pound, Ezra 20 Jul 1972
  - Powell, Justice Lewis F. 28 Sep 1972
  - Presidential Campaign 10 Oct 1972
  - Presidential Election 20 Jul, 3 Aug, 11 Sep, 2 Nov, 8 Nov, 21 Nov, 26 Dec 1972
  - Press 29 Nov 1972
  - Privacy 13 Jul 1972
  - Race Relations 30 Aug, 20 Sep 1972
  - Republican Convention 23 Aug 1972
  - Republican Party 27 Jul 1972
  - Rhodesia 31 May, 22 Aug, 8 Nov 1972
  - Snowman, Abominable 10 Oct 1972
  - Social Security 14 Jun 1972
  - Stamp Collecting 20 Sep (CBS radio), 20 Sep (TV) 1972
  - Truman, Harry 26 Dec 1972
  - United Nations 6 Sep, 21 Nov 1972
  - Victory Gardens 14 Jun 1972
  - Viet Nam 26 Dec 1972
  - Watergate 15 Aug (CBS radio), 15 Aug (TV, 15 Dec 1972
  - Women's Liberation 20 Sep 1972
  - World Magazine 21 Jun 1972
  - Abortion 25 Jan 1973
  - Air Lines 18 Jan, 8 Feb, 3 Apr 1973
  - Amnesty 8 Feb 1973
  - Bail Reform 4 Jan 1973
  - Budget, U.S. 27 Jun, 6 Apr, 18 Apr 1973
  - Capital Punishment 10 Jan 1973
  - China, People's Republic 28 Feb (TV), 28 Feb (radio) 1973
  - Columbia Broadcasting System 17 May 1973
  - Confederate Flag 8 May 1973
  - Democratic Party 18 Apr 1973
  - Dirigibles 15 Feb 1973
  - Economy and food prices 18 Jan (radio), 18 Jan (TV), 22 Mar 1973
  - Ellsberg, Daniel 17 May 1973
  - Energy 24 Apr
  - Environment 4 Jan 1973
  - Equal Rights Amendment 1 Feb 1973
  - Europe 22 Mar 1973
  - Flim Flam Game 21 Feb 1973
  - Greece 2 May 1973
  - Humor 3 Apr 1973
  - Kennedy, Edward 8 May 1973
  - Law Enforcement 14 May 1973
  - Legal Services 21 Feb 1973
  - Metric System 3 May 1973
  - Naval Discipline 28 Feb 1973
  - Paperwork, Federal 18 Apr 1973
  - Politicians 18 Jan 1973
  - Press (Shield Laws) 1 Feb 1973
  - Psycho-Surgery 1 Mar 1973
  - Reading 28 Feb 1973
  - Resolutions for 1973 1 Jan 1973
  - Rhodesia 15 Feb, 16 May 1973
  - Stamp Collecting 10 Jan 1973
  - Supreme Court 28 Feb, 29 Mar, 18 Apr 1973
  - Taxation 3 Apr 1973
  - Viet Nam 28 Feb 1973
  - Washington's Farewell 21 Feb 1973
  - Watergate 10 Jan, 8 Feb, 3 Apr, 18 Apr, 8 May 1973
  - Welfare 28 Feb 1973
- Commentaries, WTOP, Washingrton, D.C.
  - Adventurers 10 May 1973
  - Agnew, Spiro 8 Sep, 4 Oct 1973
  - Agnew Won't Resign 20 Sep 1973
  - Air Lines 27 Dec 1973
  - Air Transportation 15 Feb 1973
  - Alaska 19 Jul 1973
  - Alaska Pipeline 14 Jun, 6 Nov 1973
  - Alaska's Secession? 16 Aug 1973
  - Amnesty 22 Feb 1973
  - Anderson, Jack 1 Mar 1973
  - Arts, Aid to 21 Jun 1973
  - Auto Speedometers 4 Oct 1973
  - Automobile (Ad claims) 22 Mar 1973
  - Automobiles (seat belts) 1 Feb 1973
  - Bail Reform 4 Jan 1973
  - Bread Tax 22 Feb 1973
  - Budget, U.S. 24 May 1973
  - Budget, U.S. (Defense) 1 Feb 1973
  - Calendar, World 26 Apr 1973
  - Christmas 6 Dec 1973
  - College Students 18 Oct 1973
  - Comet Kohoutek 15 Nov 1973
  - Congress 4 Jan 1973
  - Congress (Junkets) 23 Aug 1973
  - Constitution 24 May, 20 Sep 1973
  - Consumerism 20 Sep 1973
  - Crime 22 Mar, 29 Mar 1973
  - Czechoslovakia 12 Jul 1973
  - Delta Queen 18 Jul 1973
  - Douglas, Justice Wm. O. 6 Nov, 29 Mar 1973
  - Economy 22 Mar, 21 Jun 1973
  - Economy (Price Freeze) 15 Jun 1973
  - Education 8 Feb, 27 Sep 1973
  - Elections 26 Apr, 6 Dec 1973
  - Energy (Oil; Pigmobile) 19 Apr, 29 Nov, 6 Dec, 6 Nov, 31 May 1973
  - Environment (Air) 16 Aug, 28 Jun, 13 Sep 1973
  - Equal Rights Amendment 8 Feb 1973
  - Farm Workers 19 Apr 1973
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation 6 Apr, 12 Apr, 27 Dec 1973
  - Federal Trade Commission 22 Mar 1973
  - Fish 22 Feb 1973
  - Food Labels 18 Jan 1973
  - Gray, L. Patrick (FBI) 1 Mar, 6 Apr 1973
  - Greece 27 Dec 1973
  - Gurney, Edward 8 Feb 1973
  - Indians 27 Sep 1973
  - Individuality 23 Aug 1973
  - Irish Hat 17 Mar 1973
  - Judges 20 Sep 1973
  - Kelley, Clarence (FBI) 27 Dec 1973
  - Kennedy, Edward 29 Mar 1973
  - Kissing 4 Oct 1973
  - Lawrence, David 15 Feb 1973
  - Legal Services 24 May, 21 Jun 1973
  - Medical Care 27 Dec 1973
  - Men's Clothing 12 Jul 1973
  - Metric System 30 Aug 1973
  - Minimum Wage 12 Apr 1973
  - Money 11 Jun 1973
  - McIntire, Rev. Carl 20 Sep 1973
  - Nixon (Brother) 13 Sep 1973
  - Nixon (Crime) 22 Mar 1973
  - Nixon (Enemy List) 28 Jun 1973
  - Nixon (Fish) 22 Feb 1973
  - Nixon (Homes) 12 Jul 1973
  - Nixon (Impeach Him) 8 Nov, 15 Nov 1973
  - Nixon (Impoundment) 11 Jan 1973
  - Nixon (Letters) 25 Jan 1973
  - Nixon (Tapes) 23 Aug, 24 Oct 1973
  - Nixon (his Taxes) 6 Dec 1973
  - Nixon (Watergate) 24 May 1973
  - Office Technological Assessment 29 Mar 1973
  - Oil (Alaska) 19 Jul, 14 Jun 1973
  - Percy, Sen. Charles 4 Oct 1973
  - Pornography 12 Jul, 19 Jul 1973
  - Postal Service, U.S. 27 Dec 1973
  - Presidency 12 Apr, 11 May, 23 Aug, 23 Oct 1973
  - Press (Leaks) 1 Mar, 9 Aug 1973
  - Press Council 10 May 1973
  - Privacy 21 Jun 1973
  - Proxmire, Wm. 18 Jan 1973
  - Public Monitor 6 Nov 1973
  - Puns 1 Nov 1973
  - Race Relations 25 Jan, 12 Apr, 13 Sep, 28 Nov 1973
  - Radio 20 Sep 1973
  - Reagan, Ronald 15 Nov 1973
  - Republican Party 28 Nov 1973
  - Rhodesia 17 May 1973
  - Schultz, George 21 Jun 1973
  - Secrecy 17 May 1973
  - Soviet Union 28 Jun, 13 Sep 1973
  - Television 11 Jan 1973
  - Tobacco 15 Feb 1973
  - Tricycles 20 Sep 1973
  - Trucks 29 Nov, 6 Dec 1973
  - U.S.A., What's Good 17 May 1973
  - Vietnam 22 Feb, 25 Jan 1973
  - Virginia Politics 1 Mar 1973
  - Watergate (Tapes, Segretti, Liddy) 10 May, 17 May 30 Aug, 4 Oct, 23 Oct 1973
  - Women's Liberation 23 Aug 1973
- Miscellaneous Speeches 1969-1973
  - Richmond Chamber of Commerce 23 Jan 1969
  - National Right-to-Work Directors 31 Jan 1969
  - Tennessee Manfacturers Association 14 Mar 1969
  - American Home Economics Association 24 Jun 1969
  - Charlotte Chamber of Commerce 16 Jul 1969
  - Conservative Awards Dinner, Washington 4 Oct 1969
  - Interview, Attorney General Mitchell, Washington 28 Jul 1970
  - On Agnew and the Press, Austin, Texas 21 Oct 1970
  - Virginia Press Association, Arlington 15 Jan 1971
  - Califronia Chamber of Commerce, Sacramento 21 Jan 1971
  - Young Americans for Freedom, Atlanta 12 Mar 1971
  - Notes, debate Wm. Kunstler, Univ. of Oklahoma 31 Mar 1971
  - Commencement, Prince Edward Academy 5 Jun 1971
  - Constitutional Change by Interpretation or Amendment 8 Jul 1971
  - The Restrictive Constitution, or, a Few Loving Notes by a Middle-Aged Copy Editor 9 Jul 1971
  - Southwide Conference on Elementary Education 16 Jul 1971
  - Texas Christian University 5 Oct 1971
  - Sigma Delta Chi, Washington 12 Nov 1971
  - Ford Motor Company, Detroit (ANPA Advertising) 8 Dec 1971
  - The Written Word, for Louisville Courier-Journal21 Jun 1972
  - The Sensuous Publisher 26 Jan 1973
  - Testimony on shield laws, Senate sub-committee 20 Feb 1973
  - Genesee Community College, Flint, Mich. 21 Mar 1973
  - Duke Law Forum, Duke University 10 Apr 1973
  - Associated Clubs, San Antonio 3 May 1973
  - National Governors Conference, Lake Tahoe 4 Jun 1973
  - Virginia State Bar, Fredericksburg 15 Jun 1973
  - IBM, Fort St. Lucie, Florida 25 Jun 1973
  - Interview, Senator Sam Ervin, Washington 1 Aug 1973
  - American Bar Association, Washington 4 Aug 1973
  - Pennsylvania Publishers Association, Poconos 28 Sep 1973
  - Public Policy Training Institute 30 Oct 1973
  - Randolph-Macon Woman's College 12 Nov 1973
  - St. Andrew's Society, Savannah 30 Nov 1973
  - University of Delaware 3 Dec 1973